do you have something particularly mine
has kind of dare do some sooner we done
with Tanya surpass parents after we
recorded something possible yeah yeah
questioner and I think I had in mind is
to ask you about the body
what is it what's the body so don't
flash a bug is that how you see it right
now I'm telling you yes this kind of so
from your point of view yeah which is
the only point of view you can have okay
and abstaining from assuming the
external explanatory yeah and what is
the body in your experience here and now
when you say my body my body
what are you designate thing that's the
thing I have these ideas of I think I
have those ideas for it being matter
what is the it of it without resorting
to the external ideas of what it is what
is day
it's this thing that was like that that
makes it all of this possible for me to
be sitting here talk to usual perceiving
all this tearing oh that's another
secondary idea to it but you don't see
that possibility when you look at it it
no but I do learn that about it yes I do
it but it's not it I do you think of it
as like the extent of my experience that
make you know that the kind of yeah you
know as I said once you think about it
yeah yeah having thought about it that's
what I'm sort of yeah yeah ideas I have
I mean not thought about it in terms of
all the relevant ideas that pertain to
it when I ask you it building what is it
what are you referring to you felt seen
what is it
how where why we have these
characteristic spectra of the body not
the ideas and asking that you have a
body okay so it's perceived in various
ways so the boiling right here right now
right that you have while you're talking
to me yeah perceiving various ways my
ways so well I can say it I say that but
attentive not normally look down oh you
see yeah so if you close your eyes
yeah it is it still there no well sorry
as the body yes cop the border yeah yeah
so then what is that one it's
independent of your sight
it's the cottage
let's say the center of the perspective
okay come waterside characteristics
so it's it's like
so it's not that's not so but now I was
thinking but sometimes it's like it's to
do with like things I'm doing things I'm
like like the only reason why I would
reach over there and make coffees
because the body's made that way like no
no to have a drink and - so then usage
of the body yeah he said move to the
body yeah but it's fully determined by that
yeah but it's fully determined by that
is fully made up it is the way it is
because that's the way the body is what
is weird is a good way I the way I'm
acting yeah it's just utterly it's just
like that yeah that's one minute yeah
it's secondary to the body the only way
you connect is the ways of a possible
blood line by the possibilities of the
building yeah but okay that's also such
a characteristic what would be the
primary trend realistics of it the way
it is right here right now in your
presently enduring experience I guess
well whatever ambiguous terminology
might end up using how doesn't matter
use it as long as you sort of
approximate to what it is
I was thinking man if something there's
a live something this
so just in case I don't know but don't
try to figure it out but more like just
try to keep in mind on it yeah of
strategy what comes out of 12 China
dance is something about light up just
this being alone what's the most obvious
characteristic the first popular mind if
you like it like my body right here
right now okay the secondary thoughts
about it I have the memories of the
visual images of my body from my point
of view but all of that refers to
something and that's something that
think that it
what is the calyx I see right here right
now so it's a it's a kind of container
what it but what would how would you
describe a container it's supposed to
but just in itself not know the purpose
not the possibilities just in itself
so mmm stuff matter it's dust and that
aspect of it is zero is there a feeling
yeah okay
there's one thing that inspector so is
there a feeling can you imagine the
container it the body yeah present mean
doing there for whatever it is without
also know there being a feeling present
no no no if that's the only reason why I
know is this container there is because
of those these perceptions feelings
that's why I was originally talking
about perceive disappears but again all
that can be discerned on account of it
so masking body it mm-hmm that's why I
like you thought how you're going to
perceptions and they become explanations
you lose it in the right things but the
point here is I want you I want your
mind to remain rooted on the experience
of it is to the extent that it is and it
being the body in this case you can use
that compression you go to anything
feeling mind whatever but now doing both
body yeah
so you you touch upon a matter relate to
matter can you just try them all present
enduring body material it's just like a
lump or it's like it's a something that
resists some may resists so would you
say that matter resist you to that
extent is that a mentally diseased tree
yeah it seems to think that closest
bitter part of the resistant the closest
bit of metadata resist you are the most
important yeah
the most sure the closest in and seeing
the closest bit of meta to resist you
there lies further bits of matter yeah
because what are the third of its women
all I can you know I like I'm stuck in
this room or I'm supported by this chair
that's all kind of resistance right but
that seems to be no seems to be
only seems to be secondary yeah because
it's because it's experienced via this
bit matter that yeah and also
furthermore is it did you experience the
secondary method that is Medina
how do you know that yeah since already
your experience of your body is already
a secondary experience of the mental
here so in other words it's not it's not
the body against the chair it's just
this feeling of so when you said that
the body is basically the how did you
put it it's a matter that resists you
the first mannerism is the only matter
that resists you yeah you cannot
possibly know any other matter what work
you cannot possibly know any other
matter
so it the body the lump of flesh which
already described it
Trevor you designated it as president
indeed and right here right now what so
that material aspect to the extent of
its material is there any other
accessible or experienced matter outside
of that aspect you can even experienced
matter how same experience the matter
except for apart from your body well no
you just have perceptions and and then
you can secondarily assume that that's
because this matter that assume yeah
yeah so does that mean like if you stop
assuming that there is a metal there
those things would cease to be material
what what happened then no it doesn't
mean that something that he doesn't need
so then your perceptions would basically
stop assuming letter or as the Buddha
said the perception would stop
conceiving in the metal and that's the
whole point there is no like the real
Meckler you need to figure out you just
need to stop mistaking it on the level
of a perception moral paralyzed with the
starts he perceives having perceived
that he conceives in from so the per
second that the Seca and the other hand
he directly knows that he understands l
so he realized that the perception of
mutagen that that's already what his
ignorance is yeah so that's another idea
that people who know they they they
don't have the right view so person
knows he's not a sotapanna
but thinks that he can practice the
dharma by observing his perceptions by
perceiving things purely yeah i mean you
heard that millions of times gamma toxin
was not the pure awareness the pure
perception purity of the present moment
that is already your purity is already
ignorant yet the perception already
misconceives or conceives and if mo
conceiving is misconceiving air and if
the lack of the clarity of that
that's how you picture the mistake of
conceiving and then whatever else you
build up on top of that misconceived
perception it cannot be right
and that's why multiple asset that goes
to the point of saying he perceived
Nibbana as Nibbana
but because because he perceives it as
in ignorantly
it conceives in it apart from it he
conceives the bond and mind then applies
himself yeah so it doesn't matter what
you perceive and that's another thing
when people are perceiving and observing
their sensations their movements body or
she's totally based on the basis of
perceiving perceive in perceiving
expecting the reality to come as a
result of it they need to see that in
terms of perceiving that's the problem
not what you perceive in here and that
the saving up perceiving always would
imply the self wouldn't climb it's
always is always taking foreground said
you will have to be here why because
you're not seeing perceiving to be fully
within the container of present enduring
it is experience as a whole the body
earrings yeah and yeah the only way you can
yeah and yeah the only way you can
designate it is as if the body is is
also to perceive it so that you realize
that's where your whole practice is yeah
stop misconceiving it through a
participant through your perception in
other words learned how to perceive it
on its own terms not in the terms of
your own conceiving yet yeah and that's
it that's the purification the Buddha
talks about that will require them to
see understanding of the it in the
nature time that is the characteristic
of this it then will help uncover
perception is the fact that it is just
is given it's like it is so you realize
the only reason you are conceiving
threatening you concealing things to a
perception is to not understanding that
that you're perceiving make some
difference yeah master is there
mattering and perception is they're perceiving
and perception is they're perceiving
feelings that they're feeling you're not
fully understanding that that's why the
whole notion of conceiving which means
iron mine for me and so on and
completely gratuitous talent I think so
if you want to do like the mindfulness
of the body meditation or contemplation
that's what it is clarifying what the
phenomenon of present enduring it is the
body is for me without misconceiving it
through my carelessly attending to it
basically carries attention now looking
closely enough and they're just building
my practice on top of whatever it took
for granted which is the way I perceive
things because it will just perpetuate
the wrong views further so the present
you during this body that's another
thing can you be aware of this present
enduring body right here right now in
the past or in the future no it's always
where your present is yeah can you can
you can you have leave it for a while
and then come back to it as in you
really leave the container of that body
the necessity of this body's experience
so you can't escape it it's inescapable
it seems so then any past that you
remember any future that you plan where
is it
that's all in this it's within this yeah
so is there done any need for you to
come back to the body to the present
moment so you practicing returning back
to the present moment
which is another relatively common
practice yes maintains your view that
you can leave the present moment that
you left the present moment when you be
when you started ignoring it it implies
that you can step into the outside even
if you blame it for your distraction you
still assume that it is possible to go
their way if you come whether you're
inside or outside past future present
far near big or small as the Buddha will
describe it the body is there that's
Asadabad honest understanding body a
mindfulness of the body to the extent
necessary for final knowledge develop
them dead mind Francis because that's
what mindfulness is an enduring
phenomenon of mind established upon the
body regardless of the past regardless
of the future regardless of the present
actions understanding that and Joe's
understanding that it's it's it's it's
not optional yeah it cannot replace it
you can step outside of it
you can only what you can only do is
ignore it and by doing so you become the
owner of it through misconceiving it or
you can stop ignoring it and by doing so
you stop misconceiving it and you remove
your ownership because you realize it's
impossible to own it and again that
presently enduring it it is the basis to
contain every we want to call it of any
conceivable even utter abstract
imaginative experience yeah yeah Sevigny
another question it comes out now so is
the body red body that you described in
its present enduring happen is that the
dementia no more that's an image it's an
image yeah but how does it then resisting it
yeah but how does it then resisting it
what it is how how because that image
was thrust upon we had a strategy the
body is just upon you where is that
image where is it it's it's okay for
what you want to say where it's like
there where's the image yeah where is it
where would you place it don't place
anyone asking where is it where is it
implies that it's in someone yeah the
whole notion of space is the result of
that present
exactly now so that states the whole the
division between here and yonder as in
the census sense objects yeah either way
all things are already they all
nurturing all notions of where is comes
after secondary to it to their families
images so dwelling on that will will
basically prevent you from placing it
literally in space outside of me inside
of me neither here nor there yeah
because that's what we would say stops
assuming it here younger or in between
the two years like all birthday night
yeah he's free from conceiving in and
regard and any any any notion of kind of
expectancy
waiting hoping or for a result or
something yeah anything like that always
implies outside an image of something
outside of this father so given the
practically you cannot even conceive
outside as in fundamentally yeah but
practically you maintain the view of
expectation of something from outside
yeah you realize you directly conceived
outside your solely responsible for the
existence of the notion of outside yeah
yeah and unless you address that
absolutely no amount of your effort can
result in the right practice yeah
because that's what the right right this
is undoing the conceiving I'm doing the
wrong views so the present is an
enduring body is that material and
mental at the same time depending on how
you look at it I think there is an image
yeah which is already phenomena towards
an image it's already a form of thought
but it wouldn't be there if it weren't
dependent on matter is what so then your
only relationship your first port of
call in the experience of the body as a
whole right this body here is a present
enduring image that's kind of rooted in
something else yeah not you yeah you are
secondary to it and now that's where
you're conceiving is come in trying to
repossess what what where it is rooted
in because that gives you the sense of
ownership and control but doesn't matter
how much you try to reach where it is
rooted as in the material side of the
present enduring audience am I having
that doesn't matter how trying find out
how how far you had to be you try and
reach yeah it's always step below yeah
it's always determined as a step away
from your effort inconceivable to be
otherwise that's I'm gonna said
traveling the universe will never reach
the end of it yeah
so then the only way to repossess the
necessary basis for this present in your
body does become the owner of it is to
pretend that you reached
that because of which the body is it's
the conceive it oh yeah this is the
matter things that I'm actually
secondarily only can access not even
access but relate to through the body
I assume it's that because of which this
body is here look I own this that's a on
this body thus I am my own master in
control of my experience that's why
sickness aging and death the most
uprooting basically contemplations you
can have yeah that like you realize
because it's not saluting this body of
that body it's on the routing the image
of the body that you have of yourself in
the mirror or whatever it's a protein
this currently perceived and felt a lump
of the universe that you are and you
cannot conceive outside of it so it's
only your relationship within it that's
for the bodies and that's what is
subjected to destruction and change
so is that presently during body still
there and yes I can't imagine him not
being there yeah so what any other
critics come to your mind again just
know theoretically present enduring you
have the body whether you're talking
whether you're listening what I'm saying
when you reply there is the body
enduring there what image as in what are
the characteristics now for that which
established these are mental material
image the characteristics that image
that that that I'm kind of well I said
before like I'm fine
subjected to it entirely I have to be
completely which means I didn't create
added design this I'm just all I do when
I talk to you about it describes
something that's already there yeah but
so within that that image that you said
they resist you
yeah the manifestation of that that
resistance means basically degree of
Independence yeah
toward you yeah indifference that's all
I could just die anyway he doesn't care
oh yeah of course yeah it's completely
unaware of use an area so if you were to
say develop that context of the
necessary basis of your experience of
any conceivable kind yeah doesn't even
know about your existence you don't
exist for it
yeah would there be a true statement to
say that the basis of this present
enduring Aquafresh which is mental
material basically phenomenon during the
Dhamma doesn't even know about my attempted
doesn't even know about my attempted
ownership and stuff yeah because it's
impenetrable binding and he's accessible
would you be able then if that state was
true which obviously it is even you know
after a little bit of thinking yeah
would you then or rather not would you
but more like so why are you still then
subjected to passion plus a version
designed for distraction
I guess cuz that context hasn't been
established clearly enough what context
before you just described of this this
although why would you need to why would
you need to establish it when you said
it's already there and you have no
choice but have it there yeah but it's
what is it exactly that you're
establishing then it's like I find that
when I they're recognizing that it that
it's that context is like recognizing
something that's already there
mm-hmm but that I don't always remember
there are always that I really surprised
covering whether you you get distracted
by the past timing should be distracted
from it so how is then you're forgetting
yeah of it ignoring highs then you're
ignoring and preventing you from from
understanding it because that's it why
is your immersive after that seems to be
what ignoring does ignoring then the day
the de facto response if you're
ignoring is to assume ownership it was
something weight sure you've just which
you don't own you can't home yeah so
what is that ownership then if you can't
on it it's wrong it's completely
confused it's it's so why is it then
still there
it's good questions what do you think if
it's impossible is they'll step outside
of present into a moment of the present
enduring mental material image of the
body there's obviously a is obviously an
element of wanting to order because it's
discipline it did don't matter wanting
to own it makes no difference to the
body that's unaware of your honor
yeah so wanting to own and not wanting
to own is accepting and rejecting it I
think out of it makes absolutely no
difference is the best I got it
because so why is it still there that's
that's one question and it why is it
still there
and I can satisfy because of not having accepted
ha the nature of the body not having
seen it sufficiently enough yeah haven't
seen in long enough what is the Buddha
said not having seen it to the extent
necessary for fine knowledge so in other
words you haven't been seeing it long
enough literally that it's impossible to
ignore it yeah and by virtue of that
that's why you're ignoring it yeah but
now the question is so why you they're
not seeing it sufficiently enough or the
or in other words and since distraction
can take you away from the necessary
basis of your experience for distraction
or non distraction whatever it used to
do how do you go about saying it to the
extent necessary seeing the body to the
extent necessary for final knowledge of
removing all this passion towards just I
guess like dwelling reminding remaining
yourself
about that about the father nature so no
matter the reminding of yourself yeah
why would you be doing that because it
implies that you can't forget then I go
exactly
can you forget well that's the thing
that obviously is a forgetful getting
involved so what is things okay so I get
along well how would you what is the
word of the characteristics are
forgetting generally no specifically
because it's like losing your vileness
yet is it much less yes I so what what
constitutes loss of mindfulness if the
mindfulness is present in during body
yeah that's there what do you think of
it or noteworthy past future whatever
memories you know it's there primarily
you cannot conceive experience outside
of it or independent of it so given that
it's unforgettable how can you forget
about by assuming that you can forget
about it then how do you do that
practically how does that make respect I
just ignore it but it's not looking at
it bye-bye
well I'm not looking at it so it's it
yeah yeah if you're not truly non look
at it yeah well no you cannot look at it
in a sense that you can choose to ignore
the background again I choose to ignore
this yeah means it's still there it's
still there so you can't really ignore
it
well you so you attempting it and
ignoring what is that involved what does
it involve uh doing some decal tape well
then it implies if you're doing some you
can actually do and yet you commit to it
yeah to do it what is the necessary
basis for that type of commitment
and no more practically more practically
what is it what is a common ground to
whenever you choose to ignore or engage
or something although you know you can't
only time I don't have it yet I'll not
do it a lack of authenticity but five
okay again that's on the level of the view
again that's on the level of the view
practically like say you want to
distract yourself now why would you do
that when you when you decided what or
when you when you decided what or
remember whatever you decided to
distract yourself yeah
why did you distract yourself what was
the reason for that it's not that though
because I mean offending no none of
those can be your motivations because
it's what what is pleasant doing it
doing it so all you see or you see it as
Pleasant it yeah which means it's always
basically a matter of choice upon how
you feel so that's why forgetfulness is
not a problem genuinely forgetting
things it's within present enduring
mindfulness of the of the mental
material body it's the choice you make
within that which means you're fully
aware of it that is rooted in how you
feel which is basically a choice rooted
in desire and that's the common ground
yeah desire for more desire for less
desire for neither that's why the Buddha
didn't say like oh you you don't forget
every moment of your life watch every
second of Illinois you just said avoid
unwholesome and cultivate wholesome
don't choose anything rooted in greed
aversion and distraction and if you
result in what will result in you
ceasing to maintain gratuitous notion of
ignoring that which is an ignoble and
that's why once you fully develop that
you cannot ignore it again yeah so
that's why the process of approaching
ignorance is actually completely
irreversible you cannot then start
ignoring why because what you thought
ignoring was as in when you just forget
or you decided something you're doing
something else you can't think of
everything to the same extent at all
times but you saw that that was the
reason for your ignorance it wasn't the
desire is and that is always conscious
you can ever accidentally stumble upon
decisions rooted in desire actions that
you perform on account of desire whether
for more for less subversion the
distraction whatever and that's it what
the reason why I'm coming back to this
is because that's pretty much like a I'm
one of the main stumbling blocks for
whoever starts or even like later to
develop it is assuming that you must be
in this like maintained his clarity of
though this is an honorable this is an
honorable this is an honorable every
second of your life which kind of
implies that you can still lose it very
less no you don't lose it when you don't
think about it you don't lose it when
you go to sleep you don't lose it when
you choose to do something of that's not
diluted in greed the version delusion
and that's another thing because where
people don't know where the problem is
then they blame everything to be the
problem I mustn't do anything isn't that craving
I mustn't do anything isn't that craving
isn't that a desire what I want to go
for about that'sthat's craving over
that's attachment it isn't what craving
is what desire is what attachment is
whatever you want to call it is what you
decide to act upon desire upon a version
or upon need for distraction when you
choose to act on account of I feel in
regard to how I feel so you feel
pleasantly you want to protect it you
won't have more of it you know having
thoughts of protecting it it's not in
the same level as choosing to act out of
it and that's how you maintain this
completely gratuitous Lee wrongly
assumed order that we just described it
it's actually unassuming that's how you
maintain you Detroiters ownership as
well of things that you know are
unknowable yet your ownership is there
because you still don't know what the
basis for that ownership is and your
scale asleep maintaining the basis of
the ownership and then if you look at
the basis of the ownership you say eyes
it's not having enough mindfulness its
distraction it's this is this is this
but none of that is fully understood to
the point of like as I said distraction
is not forgetting distraction is
basically choosing to distract yourself
through the means of desire to the means
of a version through the means of
distraction that's what distraction is so if you're
that's what distraction is so if you're
about to do something
oh I must stop doing no I must know
where it is rooted that's how I will
stop maintaining the bases because you
can't stop doing things because that's
not the doing it's just not doing it so
how am i doing this in order to because
of a particular feeling in regard to how
I'm feeling right now
basically you're acting out of how
you're feeling
based on that lack of context you will
be anything unafraid if you are sorry if
you're acting how on the basis of how
you're feeling yes you will
so if your acting is the cellex-c people
are not even aware of most many of the
actions because you only you're only
aware of the ones that the based on your
desire to things you want to know but
you do million of things in the meantime
you open the door you close the door or
all those are little choices that you
make there's a kind of neither wholesome
or unwholesome life which means they are
not unwholesome yeah which means you can
do it you don't have to get penalized
about what do you do what do i do then
what do I do because all the doing is
the problems no specific type of doing
doing the true sin in desire to eat it's
rooted in craving in regard to how
you're presently feeling while you're
doing it those are the ones you
shouldn't do they're too loose and let
those but when the monks tried some
monks try to make him make those still
practices mandatory for everybody should
say no to this everybody says no let
those who want to say no to such a such
life that say no to that to like living
under living in the garden roof dwelling
so let those who who want to eat one
meal a day eat one minute there let us
who want to wear hand robes wear our
clothes and those who don't want to not
do it because but that what specifically
you're doing only goes so far as in he
specifically must abstain from from
sensual indulgence chasing sense sense
pleasures sexual intercourse and all
these other things if you want full
enlightenment but that doesn't mean that
you remain like a motion is flogged for
the rest of you
until you become another no means you
just don't do things that are rooted in
desire and that's another that the
simile of the debate the hurt the hell
suta in the majima
debate about the data hurt the first one
just takes everything the second will
reject them and then the wise one is the
one that realizes no so you have to eat
as in you have to act you have to remain
engaged some extent in terms of
breathing walking sitting lying down all
of those are choices you make it's only
the choices that are rooted in desire
which is basically craving they got to
how you feel that's what you don't do
and that's what Mara will be unable to
see you and that's why you will become
free now because you stopped eating you
removed all the whole that's attachment
and no one else a the difference
that wasn't an externally nobody can
measure you exactly
including favors and Brahmans can
measure you because you don't manifest
let alone petition will be able to see
you in very respects there's no critic
for the lack of it is now can it
possibly know and that's why it's so
important because unless you clarify
this the characteristics of the present
enduring body right here right now even
when you forget when you remember you
realize this is there this is a
necessary basis for any experience
including experience of forgetting
including the experience of desire so
it's not about approaching and finding
this this this universal kind of hidden
truth that holds the whole set up on its
palm and now you got it all because you
transcended everything no it's what you
were given stop misconceiving it and you
stopped misconceiving and then you fully
understood it it's impossible to miss
conceive it isin way to conceive it or
not makes no difference things are like
this to this extent
that's what was under the law of
impermanence and even universal
principles and now it's okay so how do I
stop misconceiving it oh by not being
forgetful and so on yeah but why is
forgetfulness the problem why did it
there it's because of the desire yeah I
guess people I guess the tendency is to
kind of when you suddenly become mine
let's say you must be mindful from now
on rather than rather than recognizing
there hang on a minute I'm mindful of
something no it can't not have been
there even while I wasn't in life
exactly so instead of you when you
become mindful developing the view that
that's what mindfulness is yeah and you
have to develop more of it yeah
instead don't take their view and start
questioning further that which you
discovered through a first attempt at
mindfulness so a person is the first
attempt to mindfulness they have a set
of how it's felt how it's perceived
whether its characteristics and they
take for granted hair now the whole
point is to not take and keep going
inwardly as in digging in really further
and further not like oh no now I know
what mindfulness is now I just need to
develop this mindfulness that I know
what it is
to the extent necessary to be another
hand know the extent necessary means the
extent necessary of understanding it to
the necessary extent ever mindfulness is
about yes it's like is it right yeah for
most people they think that giving food
to Jenna knows what mindfulness is it's
just for your present now it's
recognizing a phenomenon but you have to
understand without phenomena days you
know exactly so you probably mind for
once in the stem of mindfulness you yeah
so you learn understanding to the extent
necessary that's how all did live
wholesome things will fall off what can
you say here only mindful of the body
when you understand the body is the body
exactly yeah it's are you doing it understanding
yeah it's are you doing it understanding
of the necessary basis for experience is
what mindfulness is yeah that's why the
the four foundations of mindfulness
basic understanding the four foundations
of your experience is the four
foundations of mine
there's appointment making is people
think they can do mindfulness do
meditation technique to their observance
and the only reason they can do it is
because they've you conceive them as
doable and that's why they'll never
approve that wrong view for as long as
they do it like that so fully
understanding the necessary basis of
your experience the present in yours
whether you ignore it or not makes your
mindfulness imperturbable
whatever come I mean literally if my
first Akula said mindful is properly
developed like the things of extreme
nature will not be able to perturb it
because again doesn't matter how extreme
Peaks more far near heavy life whatever
your experience is this is present
enduring there is a necessary business
for it this it the lamp of
woof-woof-woof body which is your
universe which is your whole container
which is like has nothing there is no
relationship of you can conceive on the
same footing as it is as that body
everything you can conceive it's the
words against before after it but
nothing on the level of it that's why
even you can't put it in space and say
it's in my head or it said if you do
assume that means you're not saying its
nature so any movement in regard to it
will be secondary and there was never a
problem someday young man was stopped moving
someday young man was stopped moving
because they will become your movement
the point is stop misconceiving
that which is inconceivable or stop
conceiving the inconceivable what is
inconceivable form is inconceivable
feeling is inconceivable perception is
inconceivable your attentions are
inconceivable consciousness is
inconceivable inconceivable means you
have removed your misconceiving
because when people are inconceivable
they fail to see that that becomes the
new consider you can't think that
inconceivable you can only stop
conceiving it and you stop concealing it
not by developing pure awareness to the
present need during magical moment of
your mindfulness saving it to basically
stop consuming it through through acting
out of desire
packing out craving acting out of
intentional choice on ignorance
and that's why it's doable it's all the
will enlightenment happen to me
I've been doing it for twenty if you've
been doing it for twenty years and you
don't even have the right view your
office is doing it wrong because as the
Buddha said it's impossible if
somebody's doing these things rightly
for the results to not take place like
if if a hand sits on her eggs even if
she doesn't wish me my cheeks Pierce out
of the shell safely they will because
she sits in them but if I hadn't thinks
she's sitting on her knees but no cheeks
a piece enough maybe she should really
evaluate what constitutes sitting maybe
I'm sitting in the wrong place yeah but
no it is the currently what is the
purpose of the practice of any form of
commitment to the Dhamma as a lay person
there is a monk okay you you want to
achieve something okay how are you going
about it but it's all I wanna achieve so
I have no lack of clarity of what I want
further lack of clarity of how I'm going
about it and yet here I am fully
committed to my meditation retreat to
practice and just have expect things to
occur to me and and measure basically
success by the experience of pleasure I
get from it
so is they it Bobby then we started
describing this yeah Stella
furthermore are its have had its
characteristics changed that's another
reason why people must take it into she
always remains the same so you saw the
seaweeds unchangeable yeah I guess oh
all invisible you just we stopped seeing
you in the show yeah that's actually
yeah that's your mouth anyway so you're
still subjected to it it's still that a
certain opaque lump that resists you
mmm-hmm the my life about everything
depends on it and it's still an image
yeah and you cannot even think anything
they can't even finish that sentence
with hang an image yeah can you know
that body if there is no image over
that's their the only means means that
are already materially mental or
mentally material that's now a Rupa
basic things definition yet icky there
is no Nam out of it
if there is no designated aspect of the
present enduring long it seemed consumed
as in its it's not manifested you can
rather conceive it or stop receiving you
can get either it's nothing to be
designated that's a people say I it's
all in your head it's all in your mind
it's all in your mind
it's all in the world are already on the
level of your mind which is mentally
material yeah which is something you are
subjected to
so therefore if there is that resistance
aspect to it
yeah because you had no say how that
image manifests well you can only
discern its given characteristics if you
truly were responsible for concocting it
with your designation with your naming
as people son is trying to blame the
naming for for the issue you would then
be responsible for the creation of its
characteristics wouldn't be its
characteristic it would be no it's to
designate even even like a like an
artist and they say oh yeah if you ask
them where they come from they say I'll
just I just true that things that sure
mrs. nature I'm second Raven I didn't
really create so that's the thing like
like as I said all of the five
aggregates are indifferent to you your
feelings your own intentions if you were
to the way we examine the the nature
president during body take up it's
slightly subtler to examine so I usually
just stick to the body because people
might be here in this I just get it's
already hard enough but if you do
develop skills you can do the same for
examination the same type of reflection
and contemplation you got to your
present enduring intention when you have
intention to do something yeah what is
the what are the characteristics of the
image that's a necessary container for
your intention which is the intention
you're subjected to it you chose to
attend it yeah you can only choose to
attend that which is given yeah that's
what the whole thing can be boiled down
as the Buddha said to correctly
attending things or incorrectly
attending things not correctly
manifesting and creating and then
fabricating or incorrect you know which
is that which is given on its own that
which arises manifests which induce on
its own you have a choice to attend
properly or improperly improper
attention results in increasing of
sensuality and decreasing of
non-centrality increasing of hate and
decreasing of non hate increasing of
ignorance and decreasing of non ignorant
proper attention results in office
decreasing of sensuality and increasing
of non-centrality decreasing of hate and
increasing of non head and decreasing of
ignorance and increasing of non ignorant
whether you want it or not isn't up to
you what is up to you is what you choose to
what is up to you is what you choose to
attempt yeah things are rooted in desire
things rooted in known desire things
reasoning try to change how you feel or
things rooted in not not trying to
change our Jail
so the only reason that the mind is
still not free from gratuitous
conceiving that are actually possible to
conceive is because of the choices you
make something is is that anybody
anywhere in the universe in the past or
in the future other than you they can be
responsible for this choice nothing in
Kosovo no that's another inconceivable
things yeah it's inconceivable that
anybody else can be owner of your karma
now which is a choice not a mystical
energy just in case people aren't there
so it's inconceivable that that's what
it's meant by you are the sole owner of
the choices and the results of those
choices the result being mind still not
being free that's the direct result of
the choices are still entertained the
extent of desire the extent of a version
the extent of distraction so if if if if
a question is posed why are you not in
our hand yet it's because you're
preventing yourself from being one
like oh it's my fault then if you wanna
regard in a fault
sure doesn't matter how you label it
what matters is you responsible for it
because it would be impossible to not
become another hunter if you stopped
making choices
stop acting out of choices stop choosing
basically things written in a version
delusion and distraction it will be
impossible for the mind to become to
remain unenlightened it's inconceivable
that's why if you do for such botanas as
we have said which already means you
know what they are maybe what do you
mean you can write view it's an it's
like a one way only
yeah it would only have to result in
what it cannot result in any other way